========ED=======
次回予告
OP
Onee-sama, it's morning!
御姉様　朝ですわ
ついにこの日がやってきましたのよ
This day has finally arrived!
Finally...
ついにって
今日は御姉様の晴れ舞台
Today is Onee-sama's gala occasion!
Naturally, to Onee-sama, this would seem to be something normal, but today is very special.
元も　御姉様にとって晴れ舞台など日常茶飯事でしょうが
今日は一際特別
黒子はもちろん寮生一同この日を心待ちにしておりましたのよ
Of course, I've been waiting for this very occasion, and so have all the other boarding students!
晴れ舞台ね
Gala occasion...
It's not like it has to be me. There are plenty of other suitable candidates out there.
まったく別にあたしじゃなくだって　他に相応しい人がいくらでもいるのに
Oh my, how modest you are!
まあ　ご謙遜
常盤台に腕自慢多しと言えど
Even though there are great talents at Tokiwadai, everyone agrees that you should be the one.
ここは是非御姉様にと満場一致で決まったではありませんの
まあ　決まった以上はしょうがないけどね
Well, I can't really refute the decision...
That's Onee-sama for you!
それでこそ御姉様
さぁ　さぁ　お召し替え　お召し替え
Now now, it's time to change your clothes.
I can do that without your help!
言われなくだって　ちゃんとやるわよ
決まった以上は
Since it's already been decided.
響き合う願いが今覚醒めてく
脑海中回响着的愿望现已苏醒
譲れない未来のために
为了绝不可相让的未来
巡り逢う運命を超えたその先に
只因在超越命运的前方
この想い輝くから
这份思念正闪耀着光芒
ここじゃない未来に
在那并非归属的未来
想い託してみては
寄存着这份思念
強さの本当の意味を
继续寻找着那
搜し続けてた
强大的真正意义
ありのままの痛みを
将各种痛苦
受け入れるその意味を
全部承受的意义
明日へ走り続ける君に知った
是奔向明天的你告诉了我
巡りゆく景色が今流れてく
那眼前的景色现已过去
手繰り寄せた世界の先
那紧牵着双手的世界的前方
降り注ぐシグナルを躰で感じて
身体已感觉到其中所倾注的信号
解き放つ今全てを
此刻解放所有一切
Just truthin my heart
いつだって迷わないよ
无论何时都不应迷茫
消せない想いがあるから
因为有着无法磨灭的思念
解き明かす真実から瞳を逸らさずに
直视那已经揭开的真相
I'll reach the next stage to realize all.
確かな絆信じて
请相信这份羁绊
Tokiwadai middle school girls dormitory midsummer festival
The Tokiwadai Junior High Girl's Dorm, normally not open to the public,
平素　一般へ開放されていないこの常盤台中学女子寮が
usually opens its doors once a year for one day, The Midsummer Festival.
年に一度門戸を開く日
それが盛夏祭だ
Today, there will be guests who have received formal invitations.
今日は諸君らの招待した大切なお客様が来場される
Carry yourselves respectfully as dorm students and present yourselves gracefully with sincerity and hospitality.
寮生として恥ずかしくない立ち振る舞いを持って
くれぐれも粗相をなきよう御持て成しするように
I think we could express hospitality
without wearing these clothes, though.
別にこの格好でなくても　御持て成しはできると思うんだけど
Welcome, here's a pamphlet for today's schedule!
いらっしゃいませ
こちら本日のパンフレットなります
Wow, you're cute! Do you mind if I take a picture?
君可愛いね　写真撮ってもいいかな
I'm sorry, but please refrain from taking pictures of the students.
申し訳ありません　寮生の撮影はご遠慮いただいてるんです
Ooh nice! That's nice!
Like I just said, pictures are—
ですから　撮影は
いいね　いいね
いいよ
It's not great! Why are you taking pictures?!
いいねじゃないわよ　何であんたが撮ってんのよ
誤解なさらないでくださいな
Please don't misunderstand, I'm in
charge of recording this event today.
今日の黒子は盛夏祭の記録係
Scorer
I'm taking pictures to help with
the planning of next year's event.
来年と以降の開催に向けて
こうして参考写真を撮っていますのよ
But Onee-sama, you're even wearing shorts with clothing like this.
ですが　御姉様
このお召し物にまで短パンと言うのはさすがにいかがと
せめてドロワーズを穿きになるとか
At least wear drawers...
You know, Kuroko,
あのさ　黒子
how does taking pictures of me from down there help with the planning of next year's event?
来年と以降の開催に向けて
どうしてあたしのそんな写真が参考になれるのか教えてくれないかしら
痛い　痛い　あ～痛くわ　お姉さま
Good afternoon!
こんにちは
I see you two are at it again like usual.
相変わらずやってますね
Shirai-san, thank you so much for inviting me!
白井さん　ご招待ありがとうございます　盛夏祭
To say the least, it's Tokiwadai's dorm festival!
何と言っても　常盤台中学の寮祭ですからね
It'll surely be greater than anything we might have imagined!
これはきっと私達の想像遙かに超えたものが待ち受けてるに違いありません
You're welcome. To meet those expectations, we've prepared some wonderful events.
どういたしまして
その期待に違わぬ素晴らしい催しもございますから
どうぞ楽しいんで行ってくださいな
Please enjoy yourselves.
Well then, I'll guide you from here.
では　さっそくご案内を
Please wait one moment.
ちょっと待って　白井
Shirai, weren't you going to be helping out with the buffet?
ビュッフェの手伝いはどうするつもりだ
Uh... it slipped my mind.
わ　忘れてましたの
あの
Umm...
あ～　紹介するわ
Ah, I'll introduce you.
This is Tsuchimikado Maika from the Ryoran Maid School.
こちら繚乱家政嬢学校の土御門舞夏
Her school is responsible for the food at our festival today.
今回の寮祭の料理も　彼女の学校に指導してもらったのよ
Ryoran? The maid specialist school?
繚乱って　あのメイドスペシャリストを育成するっていう
My name is Tsuchimikado Maika.
土御門舞夏である
And these are my friends, Uiharu Kazari-san and Saten Ruiko-san.
で　こちらは私のお友達の　初春飾利さんに　佐天涙子さん
Pleased to meet you.
よろしく　よろしくお願します
If anything is not to your liking, please inform me immediately.
困ったことがあれば　何なりと申すがよい
Okay Shirai, you're coming with me.
さ　白井　来るのだ
Wait please! I can't abandon Uiharu and the others!
ちょっ　ま　待ってくださいまし　初春達を放り出しては
Are you saying it's okay to just abandon work?
仕事は放り出してもいいのか
No, I'd never say something like that.
いいえ　決してそんなこと
I'll show you two around, instead.
代わりに私が案内するわ
All right, where should we go first? If there's anywhere you'd like to—
さてと　どこから回ろうか
行って見たいところとか
Yes...! Yes! Yes! Yes! There is a place I want to go! There is!
はい　はい　はい　はい　あります
行きたいとこ　あります
Here, here, here and after that here, and then finally from here up to here!
ここと　ここと　ここと　後ここからここまでを
That's everywhere, though.
それ全部じゃん
Saten-san, right now I'm not the usual Uiharu Kazari you know.
佐天さん　私 今だけはいつもの初春飾利ではありません
I've already declared this.
もう宣言しておきます
LIMIT RELEASE!
リミットを解除ですから
Well then, let's get started.
まあ　じゃあ　順番に回って行きましょう
Wow, an exhibition like this! It's just what you would expect from an ojousama school, right, Saten-san?
わ～　こんな展示があるなんて　さすがお嬢様学校ですよ
ね　佐天さん
Is this really made of sugar? It's really well made.
これ本当にお砂糖で出来てるの
よく出来てるなぁ
Let's see.
どれ
This is definitely made of sugar.
果てしなく砂糖だね
You shouldn't do that, this is an exhibition, right Misaka-san?
食べちゃだめじゃないですか
これ　展示品なんですよ
ね　御坂さん
If it's all right, would Misaka-sama have one as well?
よろしければ　御坂様も一ついかがですか
Thank you, but I must politely decline.
ありがとう　でも　私は遠慮しとくわ
Wow, this is incredibly detailed.
凄い細かいなぁ
Saten-san, Saten-san! It seems like we can participate!
Stitching class
Now you can experience it.
Please come and apply.
"It's easy"
佐天さん　佐天さん　体験できるみたいですよ
I got it, I got it, I got it, already.
分った　分った　分ったから
Misaka-san, would you like to join us, as well?
御坂さんもご一緒にどうですか
Eh, I'm all ri—
私はいい
All right, it's decided!
はい　決まりです
Three please!
三名お願いします
This is done pretty well, I think. Saten-san—
これはなかなかの出来ですよ
ほら　佐天さん
My skills have gotten worse since I last embroidered my little brother's bag.
弟の鞄の時よりか腕が落ちてるかな
How are you doing over there?
どう　そっちは
Uh... Ahahaha
This is wonderful!
これ素敵です
Ikebana = Japanese flower arrangement
Ikebana is really an ojousama thing isn't it?
生け花ってイコールお嬢様って雰囲気ですよね
It really has a graceful vibe.
こう楚々とした感じがまた
In general, it might be like that. It happens a lot in dramas, after all.
一般的なイメージだとそうかもね
ドラマなんかでもよくあるし
Excuse me, are the flower arrangements here all hand-made?
すみません　ここの生け花は全部ご自分で生けた物なんですか
Yes, of course.
えー　もちろんですわ
They're so beautiful!
とても素敵です
Thank you very much, but...
恐れ入ります
でも　貴方の御髪の花飾りの方が素敵ですわよ
Your flower headband is even more lovely.
It really is. Even more so than ours.
本当　私達なんかよりよっぽど
What are you talking about?
何のことですか
Summer's sky
Tokiwadai's dormitory is absolutely magnificent.
常盤台中学の寮祭　お見事ですわ
I'm in awe. Even if there were only one exhibition, we could never do something like it at my school.
私　感服いたしました
展示ひとつをとって見ても　私の学校では決してできないことばかり
Don't you think so, Ruiko-san?
そう思わなくて　涙子さん
How could you something like that in a place like this, Saten-san?!
こんなところで　何でことするんですか　佐天さん
Welcome back! It's just that you looked like you were so far away...
御帰り　いや　どうか遠くに行ってたみたいだからさぁ
It's not time for a welcome back, I didn't go anywhere!
お帰りじゃありません　私どこにも行ってません
All right, that should be good.
はい　これでいいわよ
Thank you very much! Umm, Misaka-sama, please do your best!
ありがとうございます
あの　御坂様もどうか頑張ってください
Ah, yeah. Thanks.
あ～　うん　ありがとう
I'm envious, getting Misaka-sama to fix your ribbon.
いいな　御坂様に直してもらうなんて
Observe, Uiharu. This is what it's really like.
ご覧　初春
あれが本物と言うものだよ
I-I understand.
な　なるほど
Hey, are you two getting hungry?
ね　そろそろお腹空かない
Midsummer
Festival
A Certain Scientific Railgun
盛夏祭
I never want to go back!
もう帰りたくありません
I'd love to live here!
一層ここに住みたい
I'll go on ahead.
私先行くね
Ah, all right.
はい
Saten-san? Are you going to take some?
佐天さん　取らないんですか
Midsummer Festival
Okay, I'll do it, then.
じゃ私が
How could you do that to such a beautiful cake?!
こんなきれいなケーキに何てことを
That's not something that someone who ate
part a sugar craft exhibition should be saying.
これはシュガークラフト食べた人の言うセリフじゃないです
Can you even eat that much?
そんなにたくさん食べられるの
When it comes to sweets, they say girls have a second stomach!
甘いものは別腹って言うじゃないですか
苦しい
It hurts...
It's because you ate too much.
そんなにいっぱい取るからじゃん
B-But it was an all you can eat...
だって　食べ放題なんですよ
Jeez, we shouldn't be acting like this in front of the students.
ったく　生徒には見せられない姿じゃん
Hey, get up.
ほら　立った　立った
If you're rough like that, I'll throw up!
乱暴にすると　逆流します
Mikoto onee-chan!
美琴御姉ちゃん
Oh, you're the one from Asunaro Park.
あれ　あすなろ園の
What are you doing here?
何でこんなところに
私が招待した
I invited them.
Hey hey, I made a bead ring and drew
ねね　ビーズで指輪作ったり　お絵描きしたりしたんだよ
I see, that's great.
そう　良かったわね
But, you know, the thing I was looking forward to the most was...
でもね　あのね　一番楽しみなのはね
うん　楽しみなのは
What is it?
Mikoto onee-chan on stage!
美琴御姉ちゃんのステージ
I'm looking forward to it!
楽しみだぜ　早く始まらないかな
When is it going to start?
Wh-Who did you hear that from?!
誰に　聞いちゃったのかな
I'll cheer you on a lot, so do your best!
いっぱい応援するから　頑張ってね
As you've heard, meet those children's expectations.
聞いた通りだ　あの子達の期待に応えてやれ
Y-Yes.
は　はい
Okay okay, don't run, now.
ほら　ほら　危ないから走っては行けません
I just said don't run in the hallway!
寮の中を走るなと言ってるだろうか
What's with that? Threatening me like that really ruins my mood.
何よもう　あんなふうに凄まれたら
返って調子狂っちゃうじゃない
Misaka-san!
御坂さん　ステージで何かやるんですか
You're going to do something on stage?
Uh, not at all...
あ～　いやいや
Hey, why did you keep something like that from us?
え～　どうしてあたし達に黙ってたんですか
Oh, I know! It's a surprise!
は　分った　サプライズだ
Eh? No... That's not how it is—
え　ううん　そいうわけじゃなくて
分りました　じゃあ　もう何も聞きません
I understand. I won't ask any more!
いやいや
No, no...
Ah, no! Don't say anything please!
あ～～だめです　だめです
何も言っちゃいけません
そうですよ　サプライズなんですから
I see! It's a surprise!
Ah, I wonder what it'll be! I'm looking forward to it!
あ～～なんだろ　凄く楽しみです
Uh...
えっと
Misaka, Misaka! Have you seen Shirai?
御坂　御坂　白井を見かけなかったか
Didn't you drag her off with you earlier?
黒子なら　あんたが先連れて行ったでしょう
She's not back in the galley.
それが厨房にもいない　さては逃げられたか
She must've gotten away.
One of the invited guests was one hell of a eater, so we're all working like crazy. It's quite annoying.
今日招待した友人の中に前代未聞の大食いがいって
てんてこ舞いなのに　いい迷惑なのだ
That Kuroko...
まったく　黒子ったら
Oh, that's right! I'm looking forward to you on stage today.
あ　そうだ
今日のステージ楽しみにしているぞ
It really is something to look forward to!
本当に楽しみですね
そうだね
Indeed!
Ah, that was delicious!
美味しかったです
次はどこ行こうか
Where should we go next?
もう決めてあるんですよ
I've already planned that.
どこどこ
Where?
If I recall correctly...
確か　このまま
Sorry.
ごめん　ちょっと　お手洗い行って来るね
Huh?
I'm going to go the restroom. You two go ahead.
先に出ていいよ
Hey, hasn't Misaka-san been out of it for a while?
ね　御坂さん　先からなんか様子が変じゃない
You think so?
そうですか
Are there any other bids?
他に入札出された方がいらっしゃいませんか
Saten-san, it looks like something's happening.
佐天さん　何かやってますよ
There aren't any more
いらっしゃいませんね
Well then, we have a winner!
では　これで落札となります
Eh, an auction?
オークションか
Hey, that's a rare brand product!
あれ　レア物のブランド品ですよね
I saw in a magazine earlier you can't get it at all in the market.
この間見た雑誌に市場じゃ全然手に入らないって　書いてありました
さすが常盤台
As expected of Tokiwadai... !
Konori-senpai!
固法先輩
You girls!
貴方達
Senpai is unexpectedly a follower of the latest fashion fads.
先輩も意外とミーハーなんですね
Normally I'm not into this!
普段はこいう物には興味ないのよ
This is for charity!
これはチャリティなの
The proceeds go to the Child Error kids!
<child error>
この収益は全額「置き去り」の子供達に寄付されるのよ
As a member of Judgement, I have to participate!
<Judgement>
風紀委員としては　参加しないわけにはいかないわ
Senpai, you sure have a lot of excuses.
先輩　凄い言い訳臭いです
I know! Why don't you two participate as well?
そ　そうだ　貴方達も　参加して見れば
え　無理ですよ　あたしたちはお小遣い少ないんですから
Eh? There's no way. We don't have a lot of money to spend.
It's all right.
大丈夫よ
The next item is... a Krugman stationery set!
さて　次の出品は　「Kirugumar」の文具セット
We'll start at one hundred yen.
まずは百円から
Two hundred!
２００円　３００円　４００円
Three hundred!
Four hundred!
See?
ほらね
Ah.
そうですね　じゃあ
TEN THOUSAND YEN!
一万円
Shirai-san, Mikado-san was looking for you.
白井さん　土御門さんが探してましたよ
I was trying to think of why you
escaped from your Galley work...
厨房抜け出して何してるのかと思えば
But buying a stationery set for ten thousand yen?
ただの文具セットに一万円って
No, this isn't just a stationery set.
いいえ　ただの文具セットではありませんの
If you must know, it's something Onee-sama put on display.
なぜならば　これは御姉様がご出品なさったものなのですから
This pencil board and notebook are
just like having another Onee-sama!
この下敷きも　ノートも
いうなれば御姉様の分身
Oh, I'm so happy!
あ～　黒子の果報者
This was Misaka's? No wonder...
御坂さんのですか　道理で
Now that you mention it, where is she?
そういえば　御坂さんは
She isn't with you?
一緒じゃないの
About that...
うん　それは
Good day to you all!
皆さん　ご機嫌よう
K-Kongou Mitsuko!
婚後光子　何ですの　その格好は
What's with that getup?
Oh my, I see your senses are very dull.
あら　さしの悪いお頭脳ですわね
今の私は　貴方にメイドのなんたるかを指南するために
Right now, I'm appearing in this outfit for the
purpose of showing you all how to be a real maid.
あえてこの衣装で参上したのですわ
Ah, how magnanimous I am!
あ～　なんていう心の広さ　慈悲深さ
Well then, please gaze at me from every angle.
さあ　さあ　隅々までよくご覧遊ばせ
Today I'm wearing a genuine-BRITISH genuine-J-A-P-A-N-E-S-E style maid outfit created especially for today.
本日この日ためだけに作らせた
純イギリスの　純和風メイド服ですのよ
A genuine-British and genuine-Japanese...
純イギリスで純和風って
Okay Shirai-san, try saying "Welcome back, Ojousama"
ちょっと白井さん　お帰りなさいませ　お嬢様　と言って見てくださる
Why do I have to do something like that?!
なぜ私がそんな事を
You can't? You should have no problem with it, since you're dressed like that.
できませんの　まったくそんな格好をしておきながら　埒もない
Please forgive me, but I don't have any experience with saying that.
ごめん遊ばせ　私そういった作法には疎くて
If you wouldn't mind, could you show me how it's supposed to be done?
よろしければ　お手本を見せていただけないかしら
Why, of course! This maid-of-maids, Kongou Mitsuko, will now demonstrate it for you.
いいですわ　このメイド　オフ　メイド
婚後光子が伝承して差し上げます
Please observe closely.
よくご覧遊ばせ
くるくるくるくる
Welcome back, Ojousama!
御帰りなさいませ　お嬢様
Good. I'm thirsty, so please prepare drinks for everyone.
喉が渇いたので　飲み物を人数分お願いしますの
Understood, Ojousama.
畏まりました　お嬢様
Thankfully, she's easy to manipulate.
扱いやすい女って助かりましたの
Good afternoon. It's been a long time.
こんにちは　ご無沙汰しています
You two must be having a disastrous time, being escorted by a person like that.
貴方達も　災難ですわね
あんなのに見込まれてしまって
She's really not a bad person, though.
悪い人ではないんです
実は今日も盛夏祭に行こうとお誘いくださったのは　婚後さんですの
The truth is...
The one who invited us was Kongou-san.
とても楽しみにしていらっして
She was really looking forward to it, and really wanted us to come.
ぜひにと
Huh, not everyone lives in this dorm?
皆さんこの寮に住んでいるんじゃないんですか
That's right. Tokiwadai has two girl's dorms, actually.
え　常盤台中学には女子寮が二つありますのよ
It's inside the Manabiya no Sono.
Wannai-san, Kongou-san, and I all live over there.
こことは別に　学び舍の園の中にも私と湾内さん婚後さんはそちらの方に
Inside that wonderful town?! In that heaven where, if you were to throw a pebble, you'd hit an ojousama?!
あ　あの素敵タワーの中に
石を投げればお嬢様に当たる楽園の中に
By the way, where's Misaka-sama?
ところで　御坂様はどちらへ
She said that she needed to use the restroom.
そうだった　先お手洗いに行くって言ったきり
Oh, I wanted to tell her I was looking forward to her performance today.
あら　今日のステージ楽しみにしていますとお伝えしたかったのに
Misaka-san is going to do something on stage?
御坂さん　ステージで何かやるの
サプライズですよ　サプライズ
It's a surprise! A surprise!
I wonder what it could be?
なんだろ
That's right, we don't have time to just stand around here!
そうですわ
こんなことをしている場合じゃありませんの
We should be getting good seats so that we'll be able to get good pictures!
良い席を確保して　御姉様のステージをカメラに収めれば
Geez, don't expect so much from me, everyone!
もう　皆って　そんな期待しないでよ
This is bad, I'm starting to sweat.
いやだ　なんか変な汗出てきた
Is this nervousness?
これって緊張
No no, I'm not nervous, yet.
いやいや　私に限って　まさかね
Misaka-sama, I wonder what kind of surprise it is.
御坂様　サプライズって何をなさるんでしょう
I'm looking forward to it.
楽しみですわね
Ooh, it feels like my heart is going to burst!
何んか私心臓が　パクパクしてきました
What're you going to do if you're nervous yourself?
初春が緊張してどうするよ
Shirai-san, do you know what Misaka-san is going to do?
白井さんは御坂さんが何をやるか知っているの
Of course! But that's for later.
もちろんですわ
ですが　それは後でのお　た　の　し　み
Look—for—ward—to—it!
It's difficult to walk.
歩きづらっ
This is bad, my heart won't calm down.
やば　なんか胸がドキドキしてきた
Get it together me!
あ　もう　しっかりしろ
Umm...
あの
がー
Sorry to distract you when you're occupied, but the truth is, I've been separated from my friend.
お取り込み中すみません
実は一緒に来た連れと逸れてしまって
Have you seen a girl this short wearing religious robes?
こんなちっこくて　白い修道服の女の子なんですけど
Why are you here...
なんでここいるのよ
Huh?
何でこんなとこに居るのかって聞いてんのよ
I'M ASKING, WHY ARE YOU HERE?!
I'm sorry! However, I'm not suspicious. Look, I even have an invitation!
ご　ごめんなさい
あ～　でも　怪しいもんじゃ
ほら　招待状だってちゃんと
Did you come here to make fun of my presentation?!
人の発表を茶化しに来たわけ
慣れない衣装を笑に来たわけ
Or to laugh about my unusual outfit?!
No, that's not it. Actually, I think you look really pretty...
いや　そんな　すげいきれいだと思いますけど
馬鹿
IDIOT!
What's with him, showing up just when I'm about to blow a fuse.
なんなのよあいつ
よりにも寄って人が一番テンパてる時に
Huh? What?
あれ
Wow, a violin solo!
凄い　バイオリンの独奏だよ
As expected of Misaka-san!
御坂さん　さすがです
Geez, he doesn't know a thing about my feelings, but...
まったく　人の気も知らないで
だけど
But once in a while, even somebody like him can be useful.
だけど　あんな奴でも
たまには役に立つこともあるのね
狙い定めた指先が指す
運命は絶望 それとも希望
ゆらぎの中で受信してゆく
悲しみにも負けない
勇気だけをください
大切なもの　守るため
「強さ」があると信じてる
Saving our future 一緒に
明日へのドア開いた空へ飛び立とう
とある世界の果てで
駆け抜けてくReal Force
光を放って
Next Episode
あれ　なんかまた　揺れてない
Huh? Isn't it shaking again?
乱
杂
开
放
Poltergeist
(Poltergeist)
Uncoordinated
Release
ゆさゆさ　ゆさゆさ
*shake shake*
The charm of your breasts is that they're not as big to shak—
そんな　揺れるほどにはないところが御姉様の胸の魅力
I'm talking about earthquakes!
地震の話だっつーの